<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
        <tumblr version="1.0"><posts><post id="183474245158" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/183474245158" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/183474245158/a-javascript-free-frontend" type="link" date-gmt="2019-03-15 16:02:52 GMT" date="Fri, 15 Mar 2019 12:02:52" unix-timestamp="1552665772" format="html" reblog-key="NtzE1fSm" slug="a-javascript-free-frontend" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><link-text>A JavaScript-Free Frontend</link-text><link-url>https://dev.to/winduptoy/a-javascript-free-frontend-2d3e</link-url><link-description>&lt;p&gt;I think this ignores one of the main benefits of JS based page rendering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the days where I worked on PHP apps, all rendering was done on the server, and that came at a great cost regarding server side processing and the complexities of peak load times, along with some pretty hairy test cases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With everything rendered in js, you are mostly just transferring static assets, so the browsers are doing the heavy lifting for you. The only things that end up taking up server CPU cycles and system memory were API calls that are easy to test, debug, and optimize. Also, those API calls can be cached, and become static assets for high traffic apis such as ones accessed on the front end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you do it all on the backend, you are doing all the rendering work, and it is hard to split off and optimize processing time for things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, for testing, it is really easy to unit test an API, and for javascript frontend work, there doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be the code regression type bugs that are so time consuming, but when you mix the data api stuff with the front end rendering, unit testing becomes a big mess.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bloat needs to be thought about, especially for limiting bandwidth, but just for curiosity, I checked out my own website which was using React and a bunch of libraries, and it was only 500K. This is about half the size of the banner image on that article. Some libraries are much larger than React, but going JS free and losing the power React gives you doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like a good trade off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course if you get some happys from being an ultra-purist, then I get that, and that is priceless. From a practical perspective though, this seems misguided.&lt;/p&gt;</link-description></post><post id="160087507263" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/160087507263" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/160087507263/how-vive-lighthouses-work" type="regular" date-gmt="2017-04-28 16:04:07 GMT" date="Fri, 28 Apr 2017 12:04:07" unix-timestamp="1493395447" format="html" reblog-key="HiqQEOgL" slug="how-vive-lighthouses-work" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>How Vive Lighthouses work</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;figure data-orig-width="800" data-orig-height="350" class="tmblr-full"&gt;&lt;img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/281359cf15eb89374c6493aa28d620b8/tumblr_inline_op4ndxrhm71qzjh7o_540.png" alt="image" data-orig-width="800" data-orig-height="350"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A great explanation of how the vive lighthouses work:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://hackaday.com/2016/12/21/alan-yates-why-valves-lighthouse-cant-work/"&gt;http://hackaday.com/2016/12/21/alan-yates-why-valves-lighthouse-cant-work/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;My short-short summary:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a rotating vertical beam from the lighthouse that happens at a very regular speed (60 sweeps per second), and a pulse that happens whenever the beam is at a specific point. You measure the difference in time from the pulse and when the beam has swept your point, any you know the angle of the beam at that point, and therefore your own angle. If you have two lighthouses, you can figure out two angles, which gives the position of any sensor on a the horizontal plane. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Each light house actually has two sweeping beams, and the second one sweeps vertically, so then with the two lighthouses, you can figure out the vertical position for any sensor.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then you throw on a bunch of sensors on your devices all doing this together, and each getting their position, and then you can figure out the orientation of any device (and the extra sensors can compensate for any errors or things that might be blocking). &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This makes for a very good positional system (down to the micron level), but the problem is 60 sweeps per second means there is some time in between (1/60th of a second) where the system doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any updates. That seems pretty minor, but we can move fast, especially when battling aliens. So in between sweeps, the devices use an inertial system that uses dead reckoning to figure out your acceleration in different directions and compensate for position changes. This can be pretty precise, and is actually how missiles and ships, and pretty much everything tracked position before gps. It does lead to drift over time, but 1/60th of a second later, it is corrected for, and so it drift doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All in all, a brilliant piece of technology. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, listen to Alan Yates, and hear even more details about different motor types, circuitry issues, lens problems, and all the other minutia that had to be conquered to get this out in the market. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="157950006648" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/157950006648" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/157950006648" type="photo" date-gmt="2017-03-03 18:22:52 GMT" date="Fri, 03 Mar 2017 13:22:52" unix-timestamp="1488565372" format="html" reblog-key="MwW0Cg8N" slug="" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought" width="1024" height="608"><photo-url max-width="1280">https://66.media.tumblr.com/f29071621f23859e2fe9070b8e60639e/tumblr_om94e4eala1qa0vkzo1_1280.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="500">https://66.media.tumblr.com/f29071621f23859e2fe9070b8e60639e/tumblr_om94e4eala1qa0vkzo1_500.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="400">https://66.media.tumblr.com/f29071621f23859e2fe9070b8e60639e/tumblr_om94e4eala1qa0vkzo1_400.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="250">https://66.media.tumblr.com/f29071621f23859e2fe9070b8e60639e/tumblr_om94e4eala1qa0vkzo1_250.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="100">https://66.media.tumblr.com/f29071621f23859e2fe9070b8e60639e/tumblr_om94e4eala1qa0vkzo1_100.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="75">https://66.media.tumblr.com/f29071621f23859e2fe9070b8e60639e/tumblr_om94e4eala1qa0vkzo1_75sq.jpg</photo-url></post><post id="157819004193" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/157819004193" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/157819004193" type="photo" date-gmt="2017-02-28 12:19:19 GMT" date="Tue, 28 Feb 2017 07:19:19" unix-timestamp="1488284359" format="html" reblog-key="r3Dtzlh8" slug="" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought" width="1024" height="608"><photo-url max-width="1280">https://66.media.tumblr.com/f29071621f23859e2fe9070b8e60639e/tumblr_om33k7uFtd1qa0vkzo1_1280.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="500">https://66.media.tumblr.com/f29071621f23859e2fe9070b8e60639e/tumblr_om33k7uFtd1qa0vkzo1_500.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="400">https://66.media.tumblr.com/f29071621f23859e2fe9070b8e60639e/tumblr_om33k7uFtd1qa0vkzo1_400.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="250">https://66.media.tumblr.com/f29071621f23859e2fe9070b8e60639e/tumblr_om33k7uFtd1qa0vkzo1_250.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="100">https://66.media.tumblr.com/f29071621f23859e2fe9070b8e60639e/tumblr_om33k7uFtd1qa0vkzo1_100.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="75">https://66.media.tumblr.com/f29071621f23859e2fe9070b8e60639e/tumblr_om33k7uFtd1qa0vkzo1_75sq.jpg</photo-url></post><post id="149461537413" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/149461537413" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/149461537413/how-to-end-corporate-tax-avoidance" type="regular" date-gmt="2016-08-25 13:33:29 GMT" date="Thu, 25 Aug 2016 09:33:29" unix-timestamp="1472132009" format="html" reblog-key="XmWrwyvy" slug="how-to-end-corporate-tax-avoidance" state="draft" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>How to End Corporate Tax Avoidance</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;2.4 Trillion are held by corporations overseas to avoid paying taxes. [1] This and a myriad of other tax loopholes allow corporations to &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;To put it into context, the IRS collects collects 1 Trillion in taxes per year. Tax rate on personal income is usually around 25%. The annual budget deficit is $194B [1]. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;[1] &lt;a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2015-03-04/u-s-companies-are-stashing-2-1-trillion-overseas-to-avoid-taxes"&gt;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2015-03-04/u-s-companies-are-stashing-2-1-trillion-overseas-to-avoid-taxes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="77710428694" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/77710428694" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/77710428694/mindwall" type="regular" date-gmt="2014-02-24 16:41:31 GMT" date="Mon, 24 Feb 2014 11:41:31" unix-timestamp="1393260091" format="html" reblog-key="spe2B0z8" slug="mindwall" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>Mindwall</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite mobile apps is Mind Wall. It is a simple puzzle game where you need to chip off one square of a wall to fit a tetris like block through the wall. It is mildly challenging, and makes for a good spacial puzzle. It was created for #ld48 &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;iOS:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mind-wall-universal/id320170750?mt=8"&gt;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mind-wall-universal/id320170750?mt=8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Android: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rtsoft.rtmindwall&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rtsoft.rtmindwall&amp;amp;hl=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="73631165664" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/73631165664" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/73631165664/save-money-on-fashion-and-luxury-ecommerce-sites" type="regular" date-gmt="2014-01-17 18:31:51 GMT" date="Fri, 17 Jan 2014 13:31:51" unix-timestamp="1389983511" format="html" reblog-key="XvjfBwMH" slug="save-money-on-fashion-and-luxury-ecommerce-sites" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>Save money on fashion and luxury ecommerce sites. </regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;I used to work in e-commerce, and one term you might not heard of is called an &amp;ldquo;abandoned cart.&amp;rdquo; It is when a user is about to check out, but then leaves the site. This happens frequently, and many savvy e-commerce sites try to recover these abandoned carts.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;If you got through much of the process including entering your email address, and abandon, the e-commerce site might send you an email within 24 hours to recover your cart and get some discount on checkout. This happens a lot on fashion and luxury purchase websites which have big markups from their production costs, and thus they can shave off a sizable percentage and still make a profit. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;So if you are on such a website, go through to the last page of checkout, and leave. Check your email (and your spam folder the next day) and you might have a surprise waiting for you. &lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="73607091303" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/73607091303" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/73607091303/testing-out-how-to-moneyball-your-way-to-a" type="link" date-gmt="2014-01-17 12:10:41 GMT" date="Fri, 17 Jan 2014 07:10:41" unix-timestamp="1389960641" format="html" reblog-key="QDuO1CwU" slug="testing-out-how-to-moneyball-your-way-to-a" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><link-text>Testing Out: How to “Moneyball” Your Way to a Debt-Free College Degree</link-text><link-url>http://www.artofmanliness.com/2014/01/14/testing-out-how-to-moneyball-your-way-to-a-debt-free-college-degree/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheArtOfManliness+%28The+Art+of+Manliness%29</link-url><link-description>&lt;blockquote class="link_og_blockquote"&gt;Editor’s Note: This is a guest post from Jay Cross. I don’t know about you, but I’m fed up with the ancient “college savings tips” so-called ex&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is advice I would have taken had I known when I started college. I would pass this on to anyone you know that is going to college soon.&lt;/p&gt;</link-description></post><post id="73429824427" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/73429824427" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/73429824427/amazoncom-robert-kohrs-review-of-polarity" type="link" date-gmt="2014-01-15 19:14:27 GMT" date="Wed, 15 Jan 2014 14:14:27" unix-timestamp="1389813267" format="html" reblog-key="ZOjuvAfJ" slug="amazoncom-robert-kohrs-review-of-polarity" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><link-text>Amazon.com: Robert Kohr's review of Polarity Magnetic Board Game</link-text><link-url>http://www.amazon.com/review/R15M90SDD7RJWT/ref=cm_cr_notf_fhv_prd</link-url><link-description>&lt;p&gt;This is possibly my favorite game. It is a game of dexterity and strategy. It is like a more physical version of GO, with a jedi/zen-ness to it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I bring it to a board game night once in a while, and it instantly becomes the center of attention. There is just something about hovering disks that is insanely cool.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;There is also an exciting riskiness in the game. You can try for more challenging moves, and they help you control the board better, but increase the odds of random things happening which can change the direction of the game.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Each game is unique and memorable, and major comebacks are common. All it takes is one bad placement.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is also a great game for kids. You have to be calm, patient, and focused. Also, you need to think deeply about the interactions of all the pieces, but the game is light enough that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take much teaching of rules.&lt;/p&gt;</link-description></post><post id="58355646853" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/58355646853" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/58355646853/no-database-for-nodejs" type="regular" date-gmt="2013-08-15 20:19:24 GMT" date="Thu, 15 Aug 2013 16:19:24" unix-timestamp="1376597964" format="html" reblog-key="TtB3nvPR" slug="no-database-for-nodejs" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>No database for node.js</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;So I have been using node.js and mongo for some time, and yeah, it works fine and all, but I am starting to wonder, why bother with a db at all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are using PHP each load of a page restarts the PHP app, and the only way you can have any state stored for anything is to use some database system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the case with node.js. With that, connections just keep coming into your app, and you can maintain a set of variables for all of the information: user data, friendships, messages, etc, and you could keep it in memory. Yes you have to think carefully about this as you could go too far with data retention and your app would have to start swapping, but you would remove a whole layer of complexity to your app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about when the app shuts down? Well all will be lost, but lets say you keep an object around called datastore, and that held all of your important data. It could periodically write its content to a json file which would be loaded on startup. Or you could just have a file for your users, messages, etc, so that each are treated separately. This might make them a little more manageable. You could throw in versioning, and you could also write to a temp file which would then me moved to replace the old one in case your app crashes during the write phase. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you only have one process, the app, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to connect or depend on anything. You can do your own quering/indexing of in memory data, and your data is just stored in human readable and easily backed up text files. &lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="44252091809" url="http://www.tumblr.com/blog/discretethought/submissions?44252091809" url-with-slug="http://www.tumblr.com/blog/discretethought/submissions?44252091809" type="answer" date-gmt="2013-02-28 23:56:22 GMT" date="Thu, 28 Feb 2013 18:56:22" unix-timestamp="1362095782" format="html" reblog-key="PCTWPpXY" slug="are-you-still-cheating-on-your-wife" state="submission" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><question>are you still cheating on your wife?</question></post><post id="11698069831" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/11698069831" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/11698069831/avoiding-a-deep-stack-of-callbacks" type="regular" date-gmt="2011-10-20 17:36:25 GMT" date="Thu, 20 Oct 2011 13:36:25" unix-timestamp="1319132185" format="html" reblog-key="ZfML8jhg" slug="avoiding-a-deep-stack-of-callbacks" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>Avoiding a deep stack of callbacks</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;When working with mongodb especially, but also in other cases, you can create a deep stack of calls that can get pretty ugly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid this I created a function that will recursively go through an array of things you want to process in a callback stack:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;utils.callbackStack = function(stack){
        var params = stack.shift();
        if(!params)
            return;
        if(params.no_params){
            params.f();
        }else{
            params.f(params, function(){utils.callbackStack(stack)});
        }
 }
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now when you want to create a stack to interate through, first create the function. For this example I am using something that adds the vision of a ship in a game to req.data.vision (these details don&amp;rsquo;t matter).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;       addToVision = function(p, callback){
            //p is short for params                                                                                                                                       
            db.
                c(p.collection).
                find(p.query).
                toArray(function(err, objs){
                    req.data.vision[p.collection] = db.arrayToObject(objs);
                    callback();
                });

        }
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I can define the stack. The f attribute defines the function to run with a passed in paramaters object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;        var add_vision_stack = [
            {collection:'ship', query:ship_query, f:addToVision},
            {collection:'port', query:query, f:addToVision},
            {collection:'cannon_shot', query:query, f:addToVision},
            {f:next, no_params:true}
        ];
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Function &amp;ldquo;next&amp;rdquo; is is just some other function I want to execute after the stack is finished. This also illustrates that you can use a variety of functions in the stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we call:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;utils.callbackStack(add_vision_stack);
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to begin the operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The callbackStack function can be re-used in a variety of situations where you don&amp;rsquo;t want to see something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;var useFile = function(filename,callback){
    posix.stat(filename).addCallback(function (stats) {
        posix.open(filename, process.O_RDONLY, 0666).addCallback(function (fd) {
            posix.read(fd, stats.size, 0).addCallback(function(contents){
                callback(contents);
                sys.debug("useFile callback returned");
            });
            sys.debug("read returned");
        });
        sys.debug("open returned");
    });
    sys.debug("stat returned");
};

//source: &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1809619/managing-lots-of-callback-recursion-in-nodejs"&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1809619/managing-lots-of-callback-recursion-in-nodejs&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;</regular-body><tag>javascript</tag><tag>node.js</tag></post><post id="8959640747" url="http://www.tumblr.com/blog/discretethought/submissions?8959640747" url-with-slug="http://www.tumblr.com/blog/discretethought/submissions?8959640747" type="answer" date-gmt="2011-08-15 22:36:11 GMT" date="Mon, 15 Aug 2011 18:36:11" unix-timestamp="1313447771" format="html" reblog-key="LOX4HlYe" slug="what-is-your-favorite-inanimate-object" state="submission" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><question>WHAT IS YOUR FAVORITE INANIMATE OBJECT?</question></post><post id="2504915219" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/2504915219" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/2504915219/automatic-localizations-for-sites-using-php" type="regular" date-gmt="2010-12-29 01:01:00 GMT" date="Tue, 28 Dec 2010 20:01:00" unix-timestamp="1293584460" format="html" reblog-key="AoQbcYgU" slug="automatic-localizations-for-sites-using-php" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>Automatic localizations for sites using PHP</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;If you have a site that you want to attract a lot of people to, one way is to translate the site into every language under the sun. This makes it so someone speaking some other language types in a few keywords in their native language will hit your site. Being most of the web is in english, this makes for some easy high ranking results in google. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to do it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wrap any piece of text in your html like so &amp;lt;?=t(&amp;lsquo;Some text)?&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create a function called t which will either:   
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;pull from the db the translation of your text (if it exists)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pull the translation from google translate api and store/return it: &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/apis/language/translate/overview.html"&gt;http://code.google.com/apis/language/translate/overview.html&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create some url pattern that will be used to identify the language. This could be either a sub-domain or a part of the uri&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;profit?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</regular-body><tag>seo</tag><tag>localization</tag></post><post id="2504717808" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/2504717808" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/2504717808/seo-friendly-ajax-links" type="regular" date-gmt="2010-12-29 00:46:00 GMT" date="Tue, 28 Dec 2010 19:46:00" unix-timestamp="1293583560" format="html" reblog-key="vNbDO7QF" slug="seo-friendly-ajax-links" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>SEO friendly ajax links</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://constantsail.com"&gt;ConstantSail&lt;/a&gt; is going to be available in multiple languages, and I put an image button in the menu which will pop up a list of links to the urls of the translated sites (example: &lt;a href="http://contantsail.com/lang-es/"&gt;http://contantsail.com/lang-es/&lt;/a&gt; for spanish).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The popup is a javascript reveal of a div (ok so it isn&amp;rsquo;t really ajax), but I wanted google&amp;rsquo;s crawler to actually go to the page with the list of links to the translations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I did was create a link with the href pointing to the url I wanted google to go, and an onclick event that did the popup and return false (so that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t follow the href).   If this would be pulled from actual ajax, this would be even more helpful since google can index all that fine content that would have been hidden behind the ajax call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;ldquo;/languages/&amp;rdquo; onclick=&amp;ldquo;$(&amp;rsquo;#languages&amp;rsquo;).show();return false;&amp;rdquo;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could replace $(&amp;rsquo;#languages&amp;rsquo;).show() with your ajax call.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>html</tag><tag>ajax</tag><tag>seo</tag></post><post id="837293319" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/837293319" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/837293319/how-to-fix-healthcare-market-based-socialism" type="regular" date-gmt="2010-07-20 18:42:00 GMT" date="Tue, 20 Jul 2010 14:42:00" unix-timestamp="1279651320" format="html" reblog-key="pRHl4vKn" slug="how-to-fix-healthcare-market-based-socialism" state="private" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought" private="true"><regular-title>How to fix healthcare -&gt; Market Based Socialism</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;The US spends about 16% of its GDP on healthcare and Europe spends 9%. (&lt;a href="http://www.scripting.com/stories/2009/08/27/healthCareInANutshell.html?dsq=16222306#comment-16222306"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GDP is 13.84 Trillion&lt;br/&gt;Lets say we want to spend what europe spends, 9% = 1.07 Trillion&lt;br/&gt;That would be $3847 per person per year (304,059,724 people). &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lets just write a check to every single us citizen for that much, but make it payable only to a health insurance provider of their choice. Insurance companies can not discriminate based on the health or other features of the customer. They offer features, and a price, and the consumer buys or not. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Whatever consumers don&amp;rsquo;t spend, they get to keep a third of, the rest goes back into the system. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Remove the requirement for employers to pay health care, I think that leads to poor results since the costs are hidden from the customers (the employees). It also makes non-employees compete with employers with deep pockets for insurance plans. This is a major reason that buying your own personal insurance is so expensive. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Tax the entire population based upon a percentage of income, to achieve the amount of cash needed for this program. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The whole system becomes a simple accounting system, with no need for the govt to manage the actually health care insurance industry. Market economics take care of all the nasty details. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Other areas this could type of system could apply to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mass transit tickets (could encourage the private development of mass transit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Home and rental support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not all of these would be useful or necessary, but it is a way of clearing the burden of (mis)management from the shoulders of govt. It also makes it more apparent when you are taking from Peter to pay Paul, and could lead to a clearer reality of the govt intervention into the market. When choosing whether to have the govt build a giant workforce, or just cutting a check to citizens, the second seems more effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should also not give to some of the population, but not to others. This leads to a strange cut off point where if you make a certain amount you lose benefits, and so you lose the reward for improving your financial position. An even percentage deduction from all, will pay all an equal dollar amount. That dollar amount can then be used only for those services that match the government determined need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are obvious areas that this wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Building roads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The space program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The military&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The legal system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because they benefit everyone equally whether you pay into them or not.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="332726288" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/332726288" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/332726288/thinking-about-how-to-do-a-schema-less-mysql" type="regular" date-gmt="2010-01-13 19:10:00 GMT" date="Wed, 13 Jan 2010 14:10:00" unix-timestamp="1263409800" format="html" reblog-key="OXGHhAyD" slug="thinking-about-how-to-do-a-schema-less-mysql" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>Thinking about how to do a schema-less mysql document store</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;So I was looking at CouchDB as a possible document store, but its main problem seems to be a slow insert rate. Maybe something similar could be done in mysql.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;==Tables==&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main document storage table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;document&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;key varchar(size depends on hashing)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;document text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;document would be JSON data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may want to index fields in the documents. To do so we could have another table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;indexed_field_values&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;field&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;value&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;document_key&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;==Another way==&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could just have a documents table with autoincrementing ids:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;document&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;id&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;document text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and have a keys table&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;keys&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;key&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;document_id&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lookups, updates, and inserts would be done through the keys table to individual documents, and a single document could have multiple keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think?&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="275425030" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/275425030" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/275425030/how-to-evenly-split-a-bill-with-a-lot-of-people" type="regular" date-gmt="2009-12-09 02:02:00 GMT" date="Tue, 08 Dec 2009 21:02:00" unix-timestamp="1260324120" format="html" reblog-key="zxWqf8Os" slug="how-to-evenly-split-a-bill-with-a-lot-of-people" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>How to evenly split a bill with a lot of people frequently</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;The situation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day many of your co-workers go to lunch together. Sometimes it is just a couple of them, sometimes it is up to 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one ever has exact change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Splitting the bill is a 15 minute affair with fudging in various directions. Usually the waiter gets a nice bonus from all this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height="150" src="http://www.yankodesign.com/images/design_news/2007/11/07/keyboard_dice.jpg"/&gt;Solution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Randomly pick (phone to randomize, dice, whatever) a person to pay the full bill for lunch. On a long enough timeline this creates an even distribution of payments for all people, but also the excitement of everyone frequently being a winner (not having to pay for lunch).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limitations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This only works if the typical behavior is to evenly split the bill. If people usually pay more or less based on what they order this won&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also likely on a long enough timeline that streaks will happen (one person having to pay multiple times in a row&amp;hellip; aka bad luck). This could be limited by a rule that no person can be hit more than two times in a row.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="242811970" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/242811970" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/242811970/emacs-recursive-findgrep-in-project-directory" type="regular" date-gmt="2009-11-13 19:35:00 GMT" date="Fri, 13 Nov 2009 14:35:00" unix-timestamp="1258140900" format="html" reblog-key="Ff8giiPL" slug="emacs-recursive-findgrep-in-project-directory" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>emacs recursive find&amp;grep in project directory</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;I do a lot of work in a set of directories in a project in emacs. The project has a huge number of files, and a lot of debugging involves tracking down little snippets of code or finding files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help with this, there are two really useful commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;M-x grep-find - this will recursively find text in files in sub directories of the current directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M-x find-name-dired - this will find files that contain a string of text in a specified directory (defaults to current).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;grep-find is useful, especially since it provides links to the line numbers in the files that you can quickly jump to with a click or by pressing return on them. The down side, it is stuck to the current directory. If you want it to start at a custom directory, you can do so in your .emacs file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(custom-set-variables                                          &lt;br/&gt; &amp;rsquo;(grep-find-command &amp;ldquo;find ~/SOME_DIRECTORY ~/SOME_DIRECTORY_2 ~/SOME_DIRECTORY_N -type f -print0 | xar\gs -0 -e grep -nH -e &amp;rdquo;)&lt;br/&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should only have one reference to custom-set-variables in your .emacs, if you already have one, just add the variable to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use as many directories as you like for searching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keyboard shortcuts are also nice, so I added these mappings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(global-set-key (kbd &amp;ldquo;C-h&amp;rdquo;) &amp;lsquo;grep-find)&lt;br/&gt;(global-set-key (kbd &amp;ldquo;C-R&amp;rdquo;) 'find-name-dired)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only wish is that there was a way to specify the default starting directory for find-name-dired. Does anyone know what variable to set for this?&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>emacs</tag></post><post id="234023903" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/234023903" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/234023903/buffetts-ideal-traits-for-a-company-to-invest-in" type="regular" date-gmt="2009-11-05 16:30:33 GMT" date="Thu, 05 Nov 2009 11:30:33" unix-timestamp="1257438633" format="html" reblog-key="oBrcqad5" slug="buffetts-ideal-traits-for-a-company-to-invest-in" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>Buffett's ideal traits for a company to invest in</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;A business they understand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Favorable long-term economics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Able and trustworthy management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And a sensible price tag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also seeks companies with moats - companies with a competitive advantage that can withstand assults from a competitor.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="231953933" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/231953933" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/231953933/us-the-saudi-arabia-of-coal" type="regular" date-gmt="2009-11-03 16:17:00 GMT" date="Tue, 03 Nov 2009 11:17:00" unix-timestamp="1257265020" format="html" reblog-key="4XpCTM22" slug="us-the-saudi-arabia-of-coal" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>US - The Saudi Arabia of Coal</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;These are some random facts from an FT article I read today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;50% of electricity is produced from coal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workers at the largest coal mine in the world (North Antelope Rochelle) work 12 hours shifts with microwaves, refridgerators, etc in the trucks to keep the operation going 24 hours a day without interruption. Every day 15,500 tones are loaded up on trains from that mine, and it supplies 40% of the US&amp;rsquo;s coal needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mine has roughly 100-150 years worth of production based on current output. The US is estimated to have several hundred years&amp;rsquo; worth of coal to be recovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is estimated that the US will emit 7,550m tons of CO2 a year by 2030, which is 14% more than 2005 levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Barack Obama, president, from a coal-mining state of Illinois, backs continued coal use. He has said if the US can put a man on the moon, it can find a way to capture and store carbon.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have my doubts that there is enough push to really make that a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put carbon capture on existing coal plants woudl push operating costs up by 80%. And as Paul Forester states &amp;ldquo;If you push 20 years&amp;rsquo; worth of CO2 in the ground and it leaks out, your back 30 years. We need it to stay there forever.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could imagine us going full on clean-carbon energy producing, just to have the carbon leach out over the next hundred years, and be worse off then we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: Financial Times November, 3 2009 page 5&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="207707456" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/207707456" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/207707456/podcast-most-recent-playlist" type="regular" date-gmt="2009-10-08 18:14:37 GMT" date="Thu, 08 Oct 2009 14:14:37" unix-timestamp="1255025677" format="html" reblog-key="6YMkNHNJ" slug="podcast-most-recent-playlist" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>Podcast most recent playlist</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Problem&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use an iPhone as really an iTouch (I dislike ATT) that is used mostly to listen to podcasts in the car. One problem I have with the way podcasts are handled in the iphone is that they are all in what amounts to separate playlists, so you need to do a lot of navigation to jump to each of your newest podcasts. Not a good thing when you are driving on the highway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Goal&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, I just want to press play, and start driving, and have the ipod play the newest unplayed podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trick, set up an automated playlist in itunes, and have the ipod synch to that. When I am on the road, I go to that playlist, hit play, and I am done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Steps to set up&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open itunes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File-&amp;gt;new smart playlist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call it something like &amp;ldquo;New Podcasts&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the following settings: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_kr7jt3Mp781qzjh7o.png"/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;click on your ipod/iphone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on the &amp;ldquo;music&amp;rdquo; tab (not the podcasts one)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the smart playlist you created&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sync&amp;hellip; and you are done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the ipod itself, you just go to the playlist, and it will have the newest stuff in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set my time limit on the smart playlist to 7 hours, as this is how much I expect to listen to my ipod between syncs (7 days of 1 hour commutes).&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="207698130" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/207698130" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/207698130/speedcrunch" type="regular" date-gmt="2009-10-08 17:58:00 GMT" date="Thu, 08 Oct 2009 13:58:00" unix-timestamp="1255024680" format="html" reblog-key="3lHl006u" slug="speedcrunch" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>Speedcrunch</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;Speedcrunch is a great calculator application that is available on all major OSes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://speedcrunch.org/images/kde-all_small.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works very much like a scientific calculator, with variables and complex expressions. It also gives you updates to the calculation as you are typing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though it is seems complex, it is my favorite to use even for the most basic of calculations. It is fast and the interface is simple to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and it is free:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://speedcrunch.org"&gt;http://speedcrunch.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="195400728" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/195400728" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/195400728/another-similar-project" type="photo" date-gmt="2009-09-24 01:07:12 GMT" date="Wed, 23 Sep 2009 21:07:12" unix-timestamp="1253754432" format="html" reblog-key="NO5OGJK8" slug="another-similar-project" state="published" is_reblog="true" tumblelog="discretethought" width="500" height="335"><photo-caption>&lt;p&gt;Another similar project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://hackaday.com/2009/09/20/pool-playing-robot-arpool/"&gt;http://hackaday.com/2009/09/20/pool-playing-robot-arpool/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uses augmented reality to help you play pool&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://hearts-and-crosses.tumblr.com/post/195308862"&gt;hearts-and-crosses&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://proofmathisbeautiful.tumblr.com/post/195305871/freaking-awesome-shooting-pool-on-a-virtual"&gt;proofmathisbeautiful&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREAKING AWESOME!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shooting Pool on a Virtual Surface!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found in Esquire’s Ultimate Bachelor Pad in Soho, New York, the Obscura CueLight uses a series of sensors and an overhead projector to cast images on a pool table that follow the balls around as you play. The $80,000 system (not including the table) is set up so that balls reveal a hidden image on the table, and when moving around, are traced by flames or water ripples on a liquid surface.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; Although this technology currently has no practical purpose, the creators are working on a program that would give beginners visual cues on where to hit the ball to make the perfect shot. Check out the video below to see it in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
:O&lt;br/&gt;I want.&lt;/blockquote&gt;</photo-caption><photo-link-url>http://www.mymodernmet.com/profiles/blogs/shooting-pool-on-a-virtual</photo-link-url><photo-url max-width="1280">https://66.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_kqg47i7Wpi1qzdk4jo1_500.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="500">https://66.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_kqg47i7Wpi1qzdk4jo1_500.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="400">https://66.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_kqg47i7Wpi1qzdk4jo1_400.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="250">https://66.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_kqg47i7Wpi1qzdk4jo1_250.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="100">https://66.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_kqg47i7Wpi1qzdk4jo1_100.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="75">https://66.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_kqg47i7Wpi1qzdk4jo1_75sq.jpg</photo-url></post><post id="193479536" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/193479536" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/193479536/pool-playing-robot-arpool" type="link" date-gmt="2009-09-21 17:33:07 GMT" date="Mon, 21 Sep 2009 13:33:07" unix-timestamp="1253554387" format="html" reblog-key="UOnw0B8R" slug="pool-playing-robot-arpool" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought" bookmarklet="true"><link-text>Pool-playing robot -  ARpool</link-text><link-url>http://hackaday.com/2009/09/20/pool-playing-robot-arpool/</link-url></post><post id="189516215" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/189516215" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/189516215/i-will-be-giving-a-talk-at-sun-on-multi-user" type="regular" date-gmt="2009-09-16 18:05:02 GMT" date="Wed, 16 Sep 2009 14:05:02" unix-timestamp="1253124302" format="html" reblog-key="MXGrK0Yk" slug="i-will-be-giving-a-talk-at-sun-on-multi-user" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>I will be giving a talk at Sun on Multi-user Real-time Comm via JSON and PHP</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;This will be down at Santa Clara. Here is more info:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://apache.meetup.com/49/calendar/11296104/"&gt;http://apache.meetup.com/49/calendar/11296104/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwords I will follow up with a posting here.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="184801501" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/184801501" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/184801501/why-vinyl-records" type="regular" date-gmt="2009-09-10 22:17:00 GMT" date="Thu, 10 Sep 2009 18:17:00" unix-timestamp="1252621020" format="html" reblog-key="Ay4LkFXI" slug="why-vinyl-records" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>Why vinyl records</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;I remember back when CDs came out, people tried to show whether they beat vinyl by using blind A/B tests. People either couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell the difference or said the CD was higher quality. The public was sold, and CDs become the standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now there is a rebirth of vinyl records, and some people wonder why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason why is that the A/B test wasn&amp;rsquo;t the test that measured people&amp;rsquo;s appreciation for what they were listening. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t the sound that was important. It is the experience of listening to the music on a CD, which feels cheap, mass produced, and less human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.multcolib.org/readers/resource/record_player.jpg" style="float:left;padding-right:1em;" width="140"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human ear can&amp;rsquo;t tell the difference, but just like how the lighting in a room can effect a meal, playing a record can elicit a different experience. When it comes down to it, music is the experience, not the ability to differentiate sound quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.podcastingnews.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2007/07/led-zeppelin.jpg" style="float:right;padding-right:1em;" width="140"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that music is just a series of bits that you can buy from a virtual store, records seem real. They have a weight, a smell, and a quality that you can&amp;rsquo;t compare to digital music, because digital music has none of those things. If CDs were cheap and mass produced, digital is potentially infinitely produced with zero cost, and potentially zero worth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://media1.break.com/dnet/media/2007/9/22sep25-cd-rack.jpg" style="float:left;padding-left:1em;" width="120"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So should you switch to vinyl. If you asked me I would tell you absolutely not, as my opinion would matter just as little as that digital download. If you feel compelled to, if you feel a bit of nostalgia (even for a time you didn&amp;rsquo;t live through), then stop reading now and go pick up a record player and a bunch of albums on the cheap. Because music is something not heard through your ears and bit rate isn&amp;rsquo;t what makes it great. It is about the experience.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="182833804" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/182833804" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/182833804/how-to-save-solar-power" type="regular" date-gmt="2009-09-08 14:00:00 GMT" date="Tue, 08 Sep 2009 10:00:00" unix-timestamp="1252418400" format="html" reblog-key="0ZrhoIum" slug="how-to-save-solar-power" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>How to save solar power</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;Their are big dreams among many on using solar power to have a house that is totally off the grid. I am one of those people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that the economics usually don&amp;rsquo;t make sense, and for the surface area of your roof, it is difficult to generate enough power to satisfy your electricity needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The culprit is AC power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.thermofluidics.co.uk/thermofluidicsfiles/applications/CaliforniaSolarRoof.jpg" style="float: left; width: 140px;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main advantage of AC over DC power is that it can be transmitted over long distances with little loss. This makes it a perfect match to our current electricty distribution system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strange thing is that most of the devices in your house run on DC power that has been converted from AC power. For example your computer has an inverter which transforms one into the other. This results in a significant decrease in power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to compound this, solar cells output dc power, which is then stored in a battery. When you store power in a battery, and pull it back out you there is a loss in power. This power is in DC, which is converted to AC so the house can have normal electrical outlets, devices are plugged in which convert the energy back to their native DC power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all these steps, you can see when you set up solar panels and configure it to run on a normal household setup you just wasting most of the juice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/a4/Inverter_CJC01.jpg/240px-Inverter_CJC01.jpg" alt="inverter" style="float: right; width: 140px;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to deal with this is to have DC outlets throught the house set up to pull directly from the panels when there is power, and to fall back on battery. Some AC outlets can be set up with inverters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gizmodo.com/assets/resources/2007/06/brando_3in1.jpg" style="width: 140px; float: left;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since DC power for different devices varies greatly, we need a common standard that is used for all of them, and I think the most common standard is the cigeret outlet in most cars. So many devices have adapters for this type of outlet that it would be the perfect way to power your house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would mean moving away from the AC standard, but as power generation gets more local, this may be the way to go. Without any knowledge of how much loss you experience with power conversion, I might guess that this would mean a 50-70% reduction in power loss. But who knows. If my gut feeling is right, we won&amp;rsquo;t need more effecient solar panels, we might be able to get by on what exists in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does anyone who knows a bit about power conversion want to throw their two cents in?&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>power</tag><tag>energy</tag><tag>solar</tag><tag>save the world?</tag></post><post id="178887853" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/178887853" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/178887853/systemlibraryframeworksjavascriptcoreframework" type="quote" date-gmt="2009-09-03 16:45:36 GMT" date="Thu, 03 Sep 2009 12:45:36" unix-timestamp="1251996336" format="html" reblog-key="zRaoGgFQ" slug="systemlibraryframeworksjavascriptcoreframework" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought" bookmarklet="true"><quote-text>/System/Library/Frameworks/JavaScriptCore.framework/Versions/A/Resources/jsc</quote-text><quote-source>&lt;a href="http://www.phpied.com/javascript-shell-scripting/"&gt;JavaScript shell scripting / phpied.com&lt;/a&gt;</quote-source></post><post id="178845776" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/178845776" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/178845776/my-father-says-almost-the-whole-worlds-asleep" type="quote" date-gmt="2009-09-03 15:31:16 GMT" date="Thu, 03 Sep 2009 11:31:16" unix-timestamp="1251991876" format="html" reblog-key="vhxZuA39" slug="my-father-says-almost-the-whole-worlds-asleep" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><quote-text>My father says almost the whole world&amp;rsquo;s asleep. Everybody you know, everybody you see, everybody you talk to.  He says only a few people are awake.   And they live in a state of constant total amazement.</quote-text><quote-source>Patricia from Joe Vs The Volcano</quote-source></post><post id="176380518" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/176380518" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/176380518/palo-alto-back-yard-politics-this-wednesday" type="link" date-gmt="2009-08-31 17:29:34 GMT" date="Mon, 31 Aug 2009 13:29:34" unix-timestamp="1251739774" format="html" reblog-key="9on4oLwv" slug="palo-alto-back-yard-politics-this-wednesday" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><link-text>Palo Alto Back Yard Politics this Wednesday</link-text><link-url>http://www.meetup.com/Palo-Alto-Back-Yard-Politics/</link-url></post><post id="173933169" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/173933169" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/173933169/the-rise-of-the-plants" type="regular" date-gmt="2009-08-28 15:33:32 GMT" date="Fri, 28 Aug 2009 11:33:32" unix-timestamp="1251473612" format="html" reblog-key="nxGnfLtv" slug="the-rise-of-the-plants" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>The rise of the plants</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;So as we point out telescopes out in the cosmos, looking for life, we use the earth we have as a model for that life. The interesting thing is the earth we currently have would be a horrible place to start life. The thick oceans, acid rain, and little oxygen are some of the things I think of when the first chemical elements that make up us started replicating. It probably looked a bit like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="early earth" src="http://channel.nationalgeographic.com/staticfiles/NGC/StaticFiles/Images/Show/31xx/315x/3151_birth-of-life-1_05320299.jpg" width="532" height="299"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all life were removed from the earth right now, life may never reappear here since the enviornment isn&amp;rsquo;t ideal for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My guess is if you are looking for life, you want a highly chemically reactive enviornment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes me think about the rise of the plants and the following rise of really big animals. Plants dominated the land at first and made an oxegen rich atmosphere. With so much oxegen, animal life was able to grow big, really big. What would have happened if plants existed, but no organisms existed to convert the oxygen into carbon dioxide. Would the plants kill themselves on their own emmisions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we kill ourselves and all animal life by pumping out too much CO2, would the plants compensate and grow larger, happy in this new world where they can breath easier?&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="173922287" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/173922287" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/173922287/reduce-carbon-in-the-atmosphere-chop-down-a-tree" type="regular" date-gmt="2009-08-28 15:19:00 GMT" date="Fri, 28 Aug 2009 11:19:00" unix-timestamp="1251472740" format="html" reblog-key="8KmW5qs1" slug="reduce-carbon-in-the-atmosphere-chop-down-a-tree" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>Reduce carbon in the atmosphere - chop down a tree</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;As a tree grows it captures carbon. Most of a tree is made of carbon. Once a tree reaches its full growth potential, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work very well as a carbon sink, and if it dies and decays, that carbon is released again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you chop down a tree, and turn it into paper or lumber so it can&amp;rsquo;t rot as easily, that carbon becomes more effectively stored. You could even bury it deep in the earth so a million years from now, our decendends can have cheap petrol to burn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important thing is that when you chop down the tree, you need to plant another. Then the same piece of land can sequester more carbon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would mean that the tree farming operations where the same forest is being cut down and regrown year after year make for one of the most effective way to reduce the carbon in the atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.mademan.com/sites/default/files/images/blog/09/1263/how-chop-down-tree.590x337.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="173918197" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/173918197" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/173918197/reduce-global-warming-with-white-roads" type="regular" date-gmt="2009-08-28 15:13:32 GMT" date="Fri, 28 Aug 2009 11:13:32" unix-timestamp="1251472412" format="html" reblog-key="CpXtnHJe" slug="reduce-global-warming-with-white-roads" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>Reduce global warming with white roads</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;Much of the earth is covered with black top roads which when hit by light convert light to heat. I wonder how much heat would be reflected back out into space if we used white roads insted.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="168465980" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/168465980" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/168465980/ocean-speedway" type="link" date-gmt="2009-08-21 22:33:10 GMT" date="Fri, 21 Aug 2009 18:33:10" unix-timestamp="1250893990" format="html" reblog-key="Hlvu4O0X" slug="ocean-speedway" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought" bookmarklet="true"><link-text>Ocean Speedway</link-text><link-url>http://www.oceanspeedway.com/index.php</link-url><link-description>&lt;p&gt;I am going to see a demolition derby tonight down in San Jose (I have never been to one before).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found it by using this page which lists demolition derbies accross the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wecrash.com/schedule.php"&gt;http://www.wecrash.com/schedule.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</link-description></post><post id="168452590" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/168452590" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/168452590/a-new-way-to-round-randround" type="regular" date-gmt="2009-08-21 22:08:00 GMT" date="Fri, 21 Aug 2009 18:08:00" unix-timestamp="1250892480" format="html" reblog-key="hYsQ1Te3" slug="a-new-way-to-round-randround" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>A new way to round - rand_round</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;So in grade school you are taught the basics of rounding. If the decimal portion of the number is &amp;lt; .5 round down to the integer so 5.3 becomes 5. If it is &amp;gt;= .5 round up, so 5.8 becomes 6.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is well and good if you are doing something that has an even distribution after the decimal point. But lets say that you are doing continuous small adjustments on a value and it is unlikely to be an evenly distributed set since the calculation for the adjustment will typically be the same.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;An example senerio that got me thinking about this is related to a game I am working on at &lt;a href="http://constantsail.com/"&gt;constantsail.com&lt;/a&gt;. Every minute 1 food is consumed for each crew member on a ship, but I want to do a smaller time slice of every 6 seconds which is 1/10 of a food per crew for that interval. Food is an integer in the db, so it must be rounded off in one way or another. If we just used the round function in mysql, and we had two crew members, I would be subtracting round(.2) ever time which comes out to zero. What I really want is it to return zero 80% of the time, and one 20% of the time, so in the long run, it still ends up being 2 food consumed for the two crew for every minute.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;To do this I take the result of rand() which returns a value from 0 to 1 and if it is less than D (which is the decmial portion of the value we are rounding) we add 1 to the floored value of our original number, else we just floor the value.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The equation is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;br/&gt;function rand_round(x){&lt;br/&gt; D = x - floor(x);&lt;br/&gt; if(rand()&amp;lt;D){&lt;br/&gt;   return floor(x)+1;&lt;br/&gt; }else{&lt;br/&gt;   return floor(x);&lt;br/&gt; }&lt;br/&gt;}&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="168452360" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/168452360" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/168452360/head-and-tail-super-large-outputs-and-inputs" type="regular" date-gmt="2009-08-21 22:08:25 GMT" date="Fri, 21 Aug 2009 18:08:25" unix-timestamp="1250892505" format="html" reblog-key="iGG45iIl" slug="head-and-tail-super-large-outputs-and-inputs" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>Head and tail - super large outputs and inputs</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;If ever you are dealing with a really large file in head (1GB+) and you need to grab a large segment of it (such as half the file), don&amp;rsquo;t use -n option to get lines. Instead, do ls -l to find the the size of the file in bytes, figure out how many bytes you need (perhaps a portion of the of the total bytes), and then call head -c THE_AMOUNT.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The reason is, I discovered that if you try and do it by line count, head needs to read through the file and find ever new line marker before outputing. This locked up a pretty powerful machine for over a day, and still didn&amp;rsquo;t output. Using byte count was done in a a minute.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;UPDATE:&lt;br/&gt;So one of the problems I am having is that head really doesn&amp;rsquo;t start outputing until it is finished, so I create a php program do output the top portion of a file:&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post><post id="168451951" url="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/168451951" url-with-slug="http://discretethought.tumblr.com/post/168451951/politics-and-small-fry-smashing-in-massive" type="regular" date-gmt="2009-08-21 22:07:36 GMT" date="Fri, 21 Aug 2009 18:07:36" unix-timestamp="1250892456" format="html" reblog-key="vCUk2Lga" slug="politics-and-small-fry-smashing-in-massive" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="discretethought"><regular-title>Politics And Small-Fry smashing in Massive Multiplayer games</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;Inselkampf is a game of diplomacy pretending to be a game of war. It mimics real politics in many ways. Small nations get trampled on so that the big get bigger, and the big nations have continual face offs that lead to few actual conflicts. When conflict occurs between big nations, there are massive casualties on both sides, lending itself to more future diplomacy to avoid such conflicts. In the end it is just a battle of who can be the most powerful without any direct conflict.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The problem is also inherent in all games of this nature. It is a massive multiplayer game where players join all the time and those who have been most active and join the earliest get a huge advantage. The losses of the big players going against each other is not worth the rewards and so the little guy gets trampled upon. If you took a game like StarCraft or some similar pure war game, and made it continuous and where thousands of players could join at any time, you would end up with the same thing.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;You can even reduce it down to a 3 player war game. The usually result is the two players will team up against the weaker one, and whoever gets the most out of the deal will end up winning the final 1v1.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;When you get enough players together, and put them at pure competition to each other, politics will always be the end result, as the one who gets the most players/power on their side will be the winner.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The only games where you will see a complete lack of politics is 1v1 games, and games where working together doesn&amp;rsquo;t help each individual player. Poker is an example of that, but even then, if there was some sort of secret communications allowed, probably there would be a similar situation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;So this is a common problem in wargame design. The only solutions I can see if you were to design something is to limit how much players can work together, but that really is not much of a solution. Crippling players abilities to bake a game concept work is odious.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;So lets start with a simple goal: make big players fight each-other rather than small fries.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;One thing is to spread the world out so that the cost of traveling to the small fries gets larger as they join. This still doesn&amp;rsquo;t help the infrequent player who joined early, but if they get knocked out early, they join the small fries off in the distance.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Another way to help the small fries, is to give them a military boost upon joining. So lets say the current average number of fighters per player is 1000k. When a new player joins they get that many units. This could also be set to the median if some players are enormous compared to others.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;You could also hurt the players that have large stockpiles, by causing soldiers to die out if they are not used after a certain amount of time. A similar way to do this is to increase the cost of expanding. Civ4 does this with maintenance costs for far away cities and when you have too many cities.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Both the helping out of small players and the hurting of large players also have problems. It makes it so the fun tapers off for big players who can&amp;rsquo;t maintain growth. Giving bonuses to small players creates an inflation factor where troops become worth less and less, and also new players will have huge armies that may be unmanageable until they learn the game better.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;None of these tweaks will effect political structures that are formed to consolidate power, but only effect the small fry clobbering by individual players. Small coalitions of players will still be weaker compared to larger ones, and consolidations will still happen as the smaller alliances of players cluster together to make themselves not so much of a target.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I suppose this problem is as old as man, and probably older (multi-cellular vs single-cellular). A cluster of players working together will always crush the smaller players. The strong will always crush the weak. Any game design that goes against these principles will require endless hacks and tweaks to stamp them out, and the end effect may be a game that isn&amp;rsquo;t much fun. The reason is that if the strong can&amp;rsquo;t crush the weak, the weak will never aspire to be the strong.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post></posts></tumblr>